复习练习 H：句子平衡，金发姑娘。口语英语里最迷人的
Review exercise H. Sentence balance. Goldilocks. One of the most fascinating
一点之一，是语调如何为听者预告接下来会发生什么。
things about spoken English is how the intonation prepares the listener for
正如你所知，语调的主要作用是宣布新
what's coming. As you know, the main job of intonation is to announce new
信息。不过，它还有一个次要功能，就是提醒听者
information. However, there's a secondary function, and that's to alert the listener
后面会出现变化。某些调整是为了句子
of changes down the road. Certain shifts will be dictated for the sake of sentence
平衡而发生的。固定短语和对比不会变，但描述性短语的
balance. Set phrases and contrast don't change, but the intonation of a
语调会从第二个词移到第一个词，意思并不改变。
descriptive phrase will move from the second word to the first without changing
重音变化表明句子并没有结束，
the meaning. The stress change indicates it is not the end of the sentence, but
而是后面还有内容。这也是为什么要按短语说，而不是
rather there's more to come. This is why it's particularly important to speak in
逐词说。我们第一次练习 Goldilocks 和三只熊时，
phrases instead of word by word. When we practiced Goldilocks and the Three Bears
句子都很短，所以不需要句子
the first time, we had very short sentences, so we didn't need sentence
如果不是为了句子平衡，底层描述性短语本来会按基本规则重读第二个词。
balance. All of the underlying descriptive phrases would otherwise be stressed on the
second word if the shift weren't needed. There's a little girl called Goldilocks.
She's walking through a sunny forest and sees a small house. She knocks on the door
but no one answers. She goes inside to see what's there. There are three chairs in
the large room. Goldilocks sits on the biggest chair. It's too high for her to
sit on. She sits on the middle-sized one, but it's too low. She sits on the small
chair, and it's just right. On the table there are three bowls of porridge. She
tries the first one, but it's too hot to swallow. The second one is too cold, and
the third one is just right. So she eats it all. After that, She goes upstairs to
look around. There are three beds in the bedroom. She sits down on the biggest one.
It's too hard to sleep on. The middle size bed is too soft. The little one is just
right. So she lies down and falls asleep. In the meantime, the family of three bears
comes home. The papa bear, the mama bear, and the baby bear. They look around and
say, who's been sitting in our chairs and eating our porridge? Then they run
upstairs and say, who's been sleeping in our beds? Goldilocks wakes up when she
hears all the noise and is so scared that she runs out of the house and never comes
back.